AMIT KULKARNI

Mechanical Design Engineer

Contact

Address

Bengaluru, KA, 560040

Phone

903-691-7762

E-mail

bkamit022@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/amit-kulkarni-65870082

Skills

Mechanic, Machining, Welding, Metal Fabrication, casting, product cost estimation

Excellent

2D and 3D modeling

Excellent

Product development

Very Good

Technical documentation drafting

Excellent

Design engineering

Excellent

Design concept verification

Excellent

Design Engineer with 6 years of experience in CAD modeling and product development. Collaborative team player with proven track record of delivering multiple, concurrent projects in fast-paced environments. Drives production efficiency through qualitative analysis and process redesign, Enjoying challenging briefs & able to work to an excellent standard under considerable pressure whilst presenting a positive image to clients & colleagues.

Work History

2017-05 -Current

Design Engineer

UCAM PVT LTD, Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Designed and developed components for 4th &5th axis
 CNC solutions from concept to finished product.
- New Product design and assembly verification using CAD tools.
- Design team member responsible for design projects and other drafting team members to assure drawing file formats were being implemented.
- Develop and own continuous improvement impacting CAD & PDM
- Understanding need for customer, taking initial requirement.
- Build 3D model parts & assembly using DFME/DFMA methods.
- Comprehensive knowledge of Product Management and computer-aided engineering, GD&T.
- Conduct process studies and evaluate data to improve utilization of resources by using proper tools.
- Estimated quantities and cost of materials, equipment and labor to determine project feasibility.
- Processed customer-supplied requirements into actionable design plans through critical thinking and independent research.

2016-07 -2017-04

Design Engineer

LD square technologies, Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Designed and developed components for Sheet metal design from concept to finished product.
- Design layouts, creating BOM (using SAP), drafting.
- Facilitate and support new product development requirements.
- Inspection designs, & quality of products by working on continuous improvement process.

AutoCAD Average 2D drawings Excellent Computer-Aided Design (CAD) Very Good Mechanical engineering Verv Good **Software** Solid works 2017/2020 Excellent SAP Very Good Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word Very Good Power point 2010 Very Good CATIA-V5 Good Languages **English** Excellent Kannada Excellent Hindi

- Focused on minimizing number of parts in design to reduce cost, eliminate waste, and minimize opportunities for defects.
- Estimated quantities and cost of materials, equipment and labor to determine project feasibility
- Processed customer-supplied requirements into actionable design plans through critical thinking and independent research

2014-05 -2015-07

Management Engineer Trainee

Danieli India pvt Ltd, Sricity, Andrapradesh

- Large assembly design plan & process details on projects.
- 2D layout design for customer approval.
- Assembly procedure documents & fixing time plan for projects.
- Created standardized templates for assembly process.

2013-03 -2014-03

Diploma Engineer Trainee

Danieli India pvt Ltd, Sricity, Andrapradesh

- Handle and maintain all sub assembly parts with labeling.
- Store and protect all parts in safe zone areas.
- Read and understand all drawings and assembly methods.
- At final assemble all parts as per assembly drawings with team members.
- Report daily updates about assembly to main supervisor.
- Worked flexible hours; night, weekend, and holiday shifts

Education

2010-03 -2013-03

Diploma: Tool And Die Technology

Nettur Technical Training Foundation - Dharwad, KA Mechanical tool & Die maker

Interests

Excellent

Playing cricket, Travel, long driving,